Finding Aid for Chauncey C. Wade papers, 1917-1932
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Chauncey C. Wade papers
1917-1932
Wade, Chauncey C.
0756 Aa 2 UAl
Papers of a soldier with the 339th Infantry in the Allied intervention in Russia, 1918-1920, the "Polar Bear Expedition."
0.5 linear feet
2 oversize photographs
744 digital files
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was donated by Wade Henderson Weisman, of St. Charles, Illinois, in 2007 (Donor No. 9880 ).
No further additions to the papers are expected.
The collection is open to research.
Wade, a resident of San Francisco, California was Captain, Regimental supply officer, 339th Infantry and Expeditionary Supply officer during the American Intervention in North Russia, 1918-1919.
Includes Wade's correspondence mainly to his family, during his service at Fort Sheridan, Illinois Battle Creek, Michigan Camp Mills, New York and Russia (primarily Bakaritsa and Archangel). Wade's papers also include his detailed response to a questionnaire from a student studying the North Russian Expedition and a roster of the Supply Company. Also, photographs and a photograph album. (The photograph album is available in digital form only.)
Subjects:
Wade, Chauncey C.; Soviet Union--History--Allied intervention, 1918-1920.; World War, 1914-1918.; Polar Bear Expedition (1918-1919); United States. Army. Infantry, 339th. Supply Company.; Arkhangel'sk (Russia); Bakaritsa (Russia); Soldiers--American--Russia (Federation); Ships.; Reindeer.; Sleds and sleighs--Russia (Federation); Women--Soviet Union--Work.; Forts and fortifications--Russia (Federation); Barracks--American--Russia (Federation); Weddings--Russia (Federation); Villages--Russia (Federation); Stores and shops--Russia (Federation)
Genre Terms:
CD-ROMs.; Photographs.
- Correspondence
  - (Fort Sheridan, Illinois), August 2-August 14, 1917 (Folder 2)
  - (Battle Creek, Michigan), August, 1917-July, 1918 (Folder 3)
  - (Camp Mills, New York), July 17-19, 1918 (Folder 4)
  - July 21-October, 1918 (Folder 5)
  - November-December, 1918 (Folder 6)
  - January-February, 1919 (Folder 7)
  - March-June, 1919 (Folder 8)
  - Red Guard Broadside oversize (Folder 13)
    Not digitized
    (Located at UAl)
- Miscellanea
  - Papers (Folder 9)
- Visual Materials
  - Photographs, Camp Custer, Michigan, 1917 (Folder 10)
  - Photograph album, 116 images (Folder 1)
  - Group photo, Camp Pontanezen, Brest France, 1919 (Folder 11)
  - U.S.S. Grant, (outsize photograph) (Folder 12)